[knock on door]
[door opens]
[Petraki] Mr. Morales?
Yes.
I have a judicial warrant here
for Ismael Morales.
Is he on the premises?
Um...
I don't know where he is.
[Petraki] Where are
your papers, Mr. Morales?
[Ximena speaks Spanish]
[Petraki in English]
Sounds like she doesn't
have any either.
Cuff him. Ma'am.
-[Rafael] Hey.
-[Quinn] Put your hands
behind you.
[Rafael] Get away from her!
What are you doing?
-[Ximena speaks Spanish]
-[Rafael in English]
You don't touch my family!
-[Rafael] Hey!
-[Petraki] Let's go!
-[Ximena] Mael!
-[Mael] Fuck you!
Get the fuck off me.
[Ximena screaming]
[Ximena] Get off of him!
-Mael!
-[grunts]
Leave him, guys! Leave him!
[panting]
[Hassie]
Move away from him. Now!
[Mael] Hassie, put it down!
[screams]
No!
[softly] I told you
to fucking stop.
[dramatic music playing]
[panting]
You have to go.
I'll take care of her.
Please, now, go.
[Ximena] Mael! [speaks Spanish]
[in English] No!
[Mael] You okay?
Yeah.
[Mael] Hassie, you all right?
[vomiting]
You okay, babe?
Yeah.
Do you need anything?
No.
[Yolanda speaking]
[in Spanish]
[Mael speaking]
[in English] Thanks.
[Hassie] What's this?
"Hassie."
It's from my mom.
"Dear Hassie,
I remember the way your
eyebrows move at the bottom
corners when you're angry.
I'm sure this letter
is making them do just that.
When those ICE agents
came for Mael,
I know what you had
to do to protect him.
And I know how much it must
weigh on your conscience.
I wish I could tell you
I'm happy that you got out.
But the truth is,
this situation at the ranch
is worse than ever.
Your father's time with us
is drawing to a close.
Doctors say weeks.
I believe less.
I know what you're thinking.
Who am I to ask
anything of you?
I haven't been the best mother.
But despite our differences,
I know you.
And I know what your
father means to you.
I would hate for you
to lose your chance
to say goodbye.
Never forget,
you are a Clarkman
and you will always
be one of us.
No matter how far you go,
that truth remains the same.
Hassie,
please come home."
[Mael] We still have a while
before we get there.
You should eat something.
Yeah, I just said
I wasn't gonna go back.
It is home.
It's not mine.
I know that...
that we both grew up there,
but we had very different
lives, you know?
Our parents are not the same.
You're not like them.
[door bells ringing]
-[agent] Good morning, Mel.
-Fuck...
[agent speaking indistinctly]
[tense music playing]
[waitress] Let me grab you
some coffee to start.
I'll be right back.
Let's go, let's go.
Come on! Come on!
[tense music continues]
[engine starts]
[tires screeching]
[Sawyer] I don't understand.
Who's this boy I keep seeing?
[Ximena] Visions like these
are normal for someone in
your condition, Mr. Clarkman.
What's that, um, word?
-My soul. My soul.
My soul's what?
-[speaking Spanish]
Huh?
[in Spanish]
Which means my soul
is halfway out.
Yes, pretty much.
Then help me.
That's why you're here.
Try to relax, hmm?
[Sawyer sighs]
[humming]
Tell me about the boy.
[Ximena continues humming]
Tell me when you see him.
[continues humming]
There he is.
I see him.
[Ximena whispers] Where is he?
[Sawyer] He's...
Where?
[Sawyer] He, he's by
the old keystone.
[Ximena] Who is he?
Oh! God damn it!
It's...
A dream is like anything
in this world.
The more you try to control it,
the more it will resist you.
The little bastard
won't look at me.
What is that about?
Maybe he's someone
from your past,
from your future.
Be patient.
-The answers will come.
-[scoffs]
[Rafael in Spanish]
Huh?
[Beto speaking]
[Rafael speaking]
[in English] Another one?
[Beto] It's happening
faster now.
I'm talking to my foreman.
We checked
the equipment last week.
Every step of the process,
it was all clean.
Could a virus do this?
Maybe. I don't know.
Well, aren't you
worth every dollar?
[Rafael] This could jeopardize
our milk contracts.
If this gets out there...
We need to tell
your father about this.
[sighs]
[Sawyer] How long?
Five weeks since
we noticed them getting sick.
[softly] Five weeks...
Did you test them?
Kidney failure,
but none of the tests
show what's causing it.
How many?
20% right now.
[sighs in exasperation] Fuck.
God damn it, Hunter.
You can't keep
this shit from me.
I'm handling it.
[sighs]
What did I say to you
when I signed
your adoption papers?
You said, "You're 100%
a Clarkman now."
Yeah.
Then act like it.
[Sawyer] Oh, boy, I know
what you're gonna say.
I don't know
what you're holding on to.
There's nothing left here.
[melancholy music playing]
I need you to get dressed.
We're not canceling this time.
Now, you really gotta
appreciate this whole
Feng Shui architecture.
Can you maybe just be nice?
Cordial?
[Sawyer] I mean,
this kind of looks like
a giant cock and balls.
-Sawyer Clarkman!
-What?
It's like thrusting
in the black hole
of a giant vagina.
That looks like something
Hunter could have painted
when she was five years old.
Yeah, well, rich people
like abstract art.
Yeah, I know what it is, too.
It's just...
I think it's bullshit.
My father bought that artist's
entire collection
at an auction.
[Sawyer] Hmm.
Completely took him
off the market.
Well, I can see why.
The price of this artist's work
skyrocketed after that.
Sawyer Clarkman,
so nice of you
to finally come over.
I was expecting a last-minute
cancelation this morning.
We've had a lot going on
on our side of the fence.
Where is your father?
I walk this field every morning
while I have my coffee.
Every morning?
Hmm. Helps me to think.
Gives me clarity
to listen to the land.
You know what it says?
I have no idea.
It says the future
of California is green,
my friends.
-[Sawyer] Mmm.
-[Roy] Mmm-hmm.
Top-tier photovoltaic tech.
Tracking system
that follows the sun
like a sunflower
and an energy output
that could power a small city.
I don't just
harness the sun, Sawyer.
I make it work overtime
for me. [chuckles]
But it's not the main event.
The real innovation
is underneath your feet.
Who knew that
under the warm, dusty lands
of northern California
there would be a sea
of white gold?
Lithium.
[groans softly]
That's what will drive humanity
into the next century.
[Leon] Last year,
the Department of Energy
granted a $2.5 billion loan
to finance the construction of
lithium processing facilities.
We are the ones set to receive
that same grant this year.
[Roy] 2.5 billion.
My son Leon here
is the man behind the move.
The grant money came
from his brilliant engineering.
A proposal for a lithium bull
with recyclable materials only.
-No waste.
-Impressive.
Unfortunately, the government
only gives big money once.
So if our families fail
to strike a deal,
Leon's grant money falls off.
Whatever it takes,
we need to make this happen.
Sawyer and I have reviewed
the deal, and we think
it's quite generous.
Hmm.
[Roy] You have a magnificent
property, my friend.
God knows you've
taken care of it.
I adore having this view
from the place
I conduct my business.
Twice the price of your land.
That is my offer.
You're not gonna get
that deal anywhere else.
[Sawyer sighs]
That's a lot of money.
What do you see
when you look out that window?
I see the future.
[Sawyer chuckles]
Yeah, that's the difference
between me and you, Reyes.
I see my home.
Place where
my children grew up.
Place that I wanted
to hand down to their children,
The place you're gonna
dig full of holes.
So do you enjoy it?
Working the fields?
Grew up doing it.
The question is,
do you enjoy it?
It's honest work.
I wouldn't expect you
to know what that is.
Ouch! Sis, help.
-I'm hit.
-[both chuckle]
[Leon] All right, I'm gonna
head back to the office.
You girls gonna be
all right without me?
[Rowan] We'll manage.
Hunter.
It was nice to meet you.
Pleasure.
Hope to see you
around more often.
You can live off the interest
and rebuild somewhere else.
Enjoy your final days
with your family by your side.
All your family!
With that kind of money,
you can get the best lawyers
for your Hassie.
My daughter
hasn't done anything wrong.
She doesn't need any lawyers.
Today in America,
people are ready
to believe anything.
I mean, it's...
a rumor can bury you.
We ought to know.
Rumors about an exploitation,
decimation of entire villages
in South America due to
a lithium extraction.
And now recently,
embezzlement of funds
from unions in the US.
Racketeering.
Those are horrifying rumors.
-[Susanna] Sawyer.
-I came here out of respect,
to make a decision because
I wanted to give you an answer
face to face, man to man.
My land is not for sale.
I appreciate
your time, Mr. Reyes.
-Sawyer.
-Yeah.
If you believe half of those
rumors about me to be true,
then you should know
it would be very foolish
to not take my offer.
You know, I've never been
much of a betting man,
but I always find
it's the little dogs
that create the biggest ruckus.
And you yap, yap, yap
like a goddamn Chihuahua.
So I'll take my chances.
Sue.
You've done
a lot of stupid shit.
This takes the cake.
I'm sorry.
Did you say something?
Sawyer Clarkman
doesn't listen to reason.
What a shocker.
Don't wait up.
[Roy] What are you
doing out here?
Couldn't sleep.
How did it go?
Ah...
he'll come around.
[Roy sighs]
What's on your mind?
[in Spanish]
[in English] I've told you.
You're an American.
Speak English.
You want
to get deported? [chuckles]
When I heard you talking
to the Clarkmans earlier,
you said whatever it takes.
I know what that means.
What that's meant in the past
for this family.
[in Spanish]
[in English] I need you to have
a little faith in me, Leon.
[sighs]
My mother was a very smart
and kind woman.
I see her in your face.
I'm a man of my word,
all right?
Because if a man's word
is not enough...
Neither is his signature.
I know.
[door closes]
[Ximena in Spanish]
[in Spanish]
[knocking at door]
[Rafael speaking]
[gasps, continues in Spanish]
[in English] I'm sorry.
[Ximena crying]
[Ximena speaking Spanish]
[in English] I missed you.
[speaking Spanish]
[in English] I'm sorry.
[metallic squeaking]
[in Spanish]
[Rafael laughing]
[laughing]
[in English] This is not
a good idea.
You shouldn't be here.
Yeah.
Well, don't... worry
too much, Ma.
We're just gonna
be here one night,
and then we'll leave first
thing in the morning, right?
Yeah.
It's just my dad.
I just need to see him.
[Ximena] Yeah,
I know he's not well,
but it is too dangerous
for you to be here.
Especially for Mael.
What do you mean
especially for me?
They're blaming you
for what happened, mijo.
They're looking for you.
But he's innocent.
[Ximena] Two government agents
disappear on our land.
Gunshots were heard that day.
And then the Clarkman daughter
just disappeared.
No phone. No trace. Nothing.
Of course, Mael was gonna be
the one to blame.
In no world, a girl like you
will pull the trigger.
Those two agents
were gonna kill me, and
you two were gonna be taken.
-So--
-[Rafael] It doesn't matter
to them, mijo.
What do you mean
it doesn't matter, Pop?
-It doesn't matter to them.
-It matters not, Mael.
You don't know what
it was like here
after you left.
We buried the bodies deep
in the property where no one
would ever think of looking.
Soon after, more agents
came looking for them.
[all clamoring]
[yelling in Spanish]
[Rafael in English]
Many of our workers were taken.
Families separated.
There was hell
on the property for months.
[Ximena]
But they never found them,
and rumors spread quickly.
The ICE agents that disappeared
on the Clarkman land,
and the Morales boy
who went on the run
because he was guilty.
Hassie...
I know that you did
what you did for us...
but nothing stays
buried forever.
No. I mean, what...
Then what? Would you
rather if Hassie went to jail?
Is that what we're
discussing here?
Mael, those agents
were corrupt.
It was self-defense.
She had a case,
but hiding it...
Now, you all could go to jail.
You, too, Rafa.
[sighs heavily]
I love you, Hassie.
I really do.
You know that, right?
But we must face
the consequences
of our decisions.
That's something
your father has never done.
He is the reason
those men were here.
And you know it.
They were here for Mael.
And you think that he has ever
said something about it?
You think that he ever
apologized for it?
No.
He went on living.
Like it never happened.
Don't be like
your father, Hassie.
[suspenseful music playing]
-[loud clattering]
-[gasps]
[door rattling]
Dad!
Hassie?
[Sawyer grunts]
[Susanna] What was that?
Fucking milking parlor! Shit!
-What? Your dad's out there.
-Call the fire department now.
It's burning.
[in Spanish]
[gasps]
[grunts]
Hassie.
Hassie!
[grunts]
Hassie.
-Hey. Hassie.
-[Hassie panting]
Breathe.
Breathe through your mouth.
Not your day.
Help!
You'll be okay.
-Are you okay? Dad! Dad!
-[Sawyer] It's Hassie!
Help her!
-Help!
-Hassie!
[Sawyer groans]
-I got you.
-[Hunter] Dad!
Got you.
[Hunter] Dad!
Dad!
Dad.
[Sawyer]
Gotta put out the fire.
Gotta put out the fire!
[Hunter] I know, I know.
-I called the fire department.
-[Susanna] Someone help us!
Don't...
Baby, can you hear me?
Honey, it's me.
Hass.
[Rafael speaking Spanish]
[in English] Hey,
we need to get her
to a hospital right now.
[Hunter] No, we're not
going to a hospital!
-Fuck you, Hunter! Bullshit!
-No!
We need to get her
to a hospital!
[Hunter] No, you fucking idiot!
You're not going to a hospital.
-She's pregnant.
-[Hunter] We are--
She's pregnant, all right?
Get her
to a fucking hospital now!
[intense music playing]
[Ximena speaking Spanish]
[in English] It's not safe.
Let's get her to the house.
-Susanna, come on.
-[Susanna] No, Mael, no.
[Hunter] The cops
will be all over you.
[Susanna] It's not safe.
[distant clamoring]
[intense music continues]
[Ximena speaking Spanish]
[siren blaring]
Hassie!
[Mael breathing heavily]
[Ximena] Oh...
Hey.
Hassie, look at me.
Look at the finger.
Follow.
Yeah...
You're lucky.
I... as far as I can tell,
it's just a mild concussion.
But you should
take some rest, huh?
[sighs] How's the baby, Ma?
Nothing to worry about.
I'll keep an eye on her.
Congratulations...
Grandpa.
[solemn music playing]
It's good to see you, kid.
[Baxter] Was your equipment
up to code?
Our guys just did
the maintenance check.
'Cause my deputy
knows dairy equipment.
He says right now,
it looks most likely
to be an overheated machine.
Maybe your boy's left
something running.
No, this was no accident.
Roy Reyes is trying
to fuck my family
into making a deal.
[chuckles in disbelief]
Just when I thought
I was gonna get a little break
from the Clarkmans.
[chatter over radio]
By the way,
still no word from your sister
and her boyfriend?
That has nothing
to do with this.
Because with all the shit going
on in the state right now,
two dirty ICE agents
are not my priority.
But I got the higher-ups
breathing down my neck
to close that case.
I just want to get it done.
[Hunter] And I just want
to get this done.
Now whose dick do I have
to suck to make that happen?
All right, enough
with the language, okay?
Look...
without evidence,
you cannot go around
accusing no one.
Mr. Reyes has brought
a lot of business
to our community.
[Hunter scoffs]
Roy is a businessman.
There's no way he did
something like that.
Roy has been trying
to push us out with the cattle,
-and now he's out of time.
-[Susanna sighs]
Raf, how is he
getting to the cattle?
[Rafael] We swept
the piping, we... we...
we checked
the water supplies twice,
the feed... everything.
Nada.
That is why I think it's
in this family's best interest
to take his deal.
-[whispers] For fuck's sake.
-[Sawyer] So you want
to get bought out
with dirty money by that guy?
The guy that blew up
a milk parlor next to
your pregnant daughter?
No, what I want
for my daughter
is a better future
than what exists
on this cow shit farm.
Hassie could have been killed.
It's not just about
the Clarkman name.
Oh, my God!
Clarkman! Fucking name!
The fucking legacy.
[soft tense music playing]
-[door opens]
-What's going on with her?
[door slams]
We figure out
how that motherfucker
is getting to the cattle.
It is the only way
we can kick production back up.
Let me look into it.
-[Ximena] Mael.
-Ma, please.
Let me look into it,
Mr. Clarkman.
Now you call me Sawyer.
Sawyer.
Oh, yeah, that's a great idea.
Just have the fugitives
roaming the property, sure.
Stay out of sight.
Don't go off the ranch.
[Rafael] You can trust
all the workers here,
but don't let anybody
from the outside see you, eh?
Yeah, okay.
Raf, gather the crew.
And in the morning,
I want to see them.
[Rafael] All right.
You got it, boss.
Anything else?
I'm working on it.
It's a crapshoot,
but we got nothing to lose.
Hunter, in my office.
Welcome home, Has.
[soft tense music continues]
[Ximena] Mael...
[cows mooing]
[engine stops]
You all right?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm good.
[distant squawking]
I used to think this place
was just a prison.
[pensive music playing]
I forgot
how peaceful it can be.
Yeah.
You know how much I love
growing up out here.
[Hassie] Mmm.
Great place to raise a family.
[chuckles]
[Hassie mutters]
[pensive music continues]
[Sawyer] Taking care
of this land
has always been
our top priority.
She provides for us,
she feeds us,
and she gives us shelter.
[Grant chuckles softly]
[Sawyer laughs]
[Grant] Good
to see you, old man.
Ah, good
to see you too, Governor.
And I've always been
grateful to you all for...
working the fields,
caring for the cattle.
Sowing the seeds
of our futures.
[Grant] Can you prove it's him?
Well, I wouldn't be here
if I could.
Does our arrangement
still stand?
Yeah, it stands.
He can't mine lithium...
on any land
adjacent to your land
as long as it remains yours.
But from what I'm hearing,
how are you gonna
fulfill your contract?
I'm just working on
something as we speak.
You're not making any sense.
You're presenting me
with these problems.
And I...
I have my own problems.
Well, Dick, if we go down,
everyone goes down.
You take the cattle,
split the profit.
Interesting proposition.
But why wouldn't I just
let you go under,
and then just
snatch up all your contracts?
[Sawyer] The storms are coming.
We're under attack.
This explosion here
at the milk parlor
was no accident.
[keyboard clacking]
All of our livelihoods
are at stake...
so I need you to be
on the lookout.
[Grant] Now, Reyes' offer,
that's more than fair.
You could buy twice the land
with what he's offering.
Why don't you just sell?
[laughs exultantly]
This is coming from the man
who helped his grandpa
build a 100-acre farm
with his own bare hands, huh?
And what would it take
for you to give that up?
Times change.
What the hell was
your father thinking?
If he has no cows to milk,
he has no product to deliver.
He's about to lose
all his contracts.
He has no choice.
You're welcome.
Well,
you're a real fucking gem,
aren't you, Governor?
Reyes has got you
in his back pocket.
[Grant] How can you say that?
We've been friends
for more than 40 some years.
And that is how I know,
old man.
What you do not understand
is that he is going to obsess
about fixing everything
that you've done.
Well, hopefully,
you can nudge him
in the right direction
before he kicks
the fucking bucket.
Back the fuck off.
I'll handle it.
Any stranger comes by,
you talk to Hunter, Rafael.
You watch each other's backs,
you take care of yourselves.
That's how we get through this.
All right, let's move.
I distinctly remember a time
when Nature Conservancy
was up your ass
trying to shut you down, Dick.
[cows mooing]
You run a good farm, Dick,
but you wouldn't still be here
if my dad didn't twist some
arms in Sacramento for you.
It's nice to have allies,
isn't it?
Are you gonna let this guy
walk all over you,
or are you gonna give me
something to turn the screw?
Maybe I can.
[footsteps approaching]
[inhales]
[Hunter] A little
counterproductive, isn't it?
Hmm...
It's the best of both worlds,
as I've seen.
How did it go with, uh...
-Dick Harris?
-[sighs]
He's an ungrateful
son of a bitch.
But we came to an agreement.
-That's my girl.
-[chuckles softly]
How about
our distinguished governor?
[groans] No surprise.
Reyes has him over a barrel.
But, um, I think
we found something
that we can work with.
[sighs]
What's troubling you, kid?
Reyes isn't gonna go down easy.
Yeah.
Well, that's war, Hunter.
Forget about what's right,
what's easy.
We do what's necessary.
[phone buzzing]
[enigmatic music playing]
[Leon] I've been waiting
for this for a long time.
[Hunter] We're gonna have
to make this fast.
[Leon breathes heavily]
Not too fast.
[Hunter moaning softly]
What's the hurry?
[Hunter] I'm gonna be late.
[Leon chuckles softly]
So would it be so terrible
to disappoint your father?
[Hunter] You don't know shit
about my father.
So did you figure out
when your next presentation is
for the mining commission?
[Leon] I'll hear about it
by the end of the week.
Why don't we talk about it
this Saturday?
My place, red wine,
candlelight.
Cut the shit.
I asked you a question.
And I asked you on a date.
[sighs]
Fine.
But you're still going
to give me what I want.
[solemn music playing]
Seems a little far out
for our cows, yeah?
Yeah, well,
the Clarkman property line
was back there.
This is Reyes' territory now.
Well, my dad said
we're not supposed
to leave our property.
Yeah, well, I've seen a couple
of cows grazing by some
natural springs in the area.
My dad and his guys
already checked
the watering holes on our land.
Listen, all the land out here
is connected, okay?
So whatever Reyes does
on his property affects ours.
-Okay.
-Okay, let's go.
[pensive music playing]
[shivering]
[chuckles softly]
It's not cold.
When did you get so wimpy?
[chuckles shakily]
[exhales]
[breathes deeply]
[uneasy music playing]
What's wrong?
-[Hassie sighs]
-What is it?
Are you okay?
-Huh?
-[exhales deeply]
[sighs] Oh, God.
I feel like I'm gonna be sick.
[breathing heavily]
Do you smell that?
[Hassie inhales]
[Hassie exhales]
I smell that.
[ominous sting plays]
[ominous sting continues]
[Mael softly] What the fuck?
What the fuck?
[soft tense music playing]
Look.
[Hassie] It smells sweet.
It's antifreeze.
[tape ripping]
[soft tense music continues]
[Hassie] It smells
like antifreeze.
Which has broken
down on the kidneys
before killing the cows.
Untraceable,
unless you catch it.
Yeah, you don't even
need to test it.
You can still smell it in that.
Those motherfuckers.
Was there any equipment?
Anything?
No, nothing.
Well, that means
they're doing this regularly.
Yeah, I set up
a trail cam right there.
So if they come back,
we'll know.
Good job.
Now we send them a message.
[soft tense music continues]
Reyes has invited
the mining commission
to their property on Friday.
And Leon's gonna give them
the same old song and dance
they gave us
to try and sell the deal.
Make sure that presentation
doesn't happen.
[harrowing music playing]
[henchman 1]
Let's go, let's go!
Well, hi there.
[henchman 2] Let her run, Jake!
-Jake?
-[Jake] Don't shoot!
Don't shoot!
-Don't shoot!
-[gun cocks]
Don't move, pendejo!
You fuck with my cattle again,
you will lose,
you'll regret it.
[grunts]
You like fucking
with our cows, huh?
[henchman 2]
What are you talking--
-[Rafael shouts]
-[henchman 3 grunts]
[in Spanish]
[overlapping chatter]
[grunts]
[henchman 2 grunts]
[in English] Let's move!
[intense music playing]
[Roy sighs]
[speaking Spanish] Ready?
[farmhand in Spanish]
Ready! Ready!
[Rafael speaking Spanish]
[engine revs]
[engine roaring]
[electricity crackling]
[Roy in English] What the heck?
Leon!
[breathes heavily]
[Leon] What the fuck?
Hey!
Guards!
[speaking Spanish]
[grunts]
[door opens]
[Mael in English] Hey, Pa.
[door closes]
Dad, are you... are you okay?
It's taken care of.
[water running]
[in Spanish]
[Rafael speaking Spanish]
[footsteps receding]
[Ximena in English]
I'm sorry, Hassie.
[footsteps receding]
[Roy] How long to fix it?
They ripped up the wiring
from deep in the ground.
[Roy] How long?
Two weeks, maybe more.
[Roy sighs]
Who did this to you?
You didn't see their faces?
It was dark.
Was it them?
I told you
I didn't see anything.
I need to lie down.
[sighs]
I'm canceling the presentation.
Rowan.
[dramatic music playing]
Find those bodies.
They've been buried
long enough.
[dramatic music continues]
[Leon] How could you?
You know how important
this project is to me.
[Hunter] You
and your fucking family
started this shit.
Whatever's going on between
my father and your family,
I have nothing to do with it.
I'm not like him.
You're either lying to me
or you're too fucking naive.
Either way, I can't trust you.
This project
is important to me...
but it's not worth dying for.
You don't know shit.
You're so predictable,
you know that?
You're stubborn,
just like my sister.
For all it's worth,
this show you put on,
this whole
"take no bullshit" act,
I know it's because
of your father.
And I know what that's like.
But I also know
there's more to life
than just be
another cog in their wheel.
There's more to you than this.
You can still get out.
I love that we're all here
on this land together.
And, uh...
the good moments have been
few and far between.
So...
It's no secret that, um,
I don't have the luxury
of time at this point,
so when a good one
comes along, it's, uh...
best we celebrate it.
Um...
Hassie and Mael,
and your baby...
Um...
[laughs]
If it's a boy,
you can call it Hunter.
[chuckles]
Um...
-[chuckles]
-No, shut up.
What I'm trying
to say is, uh...
[sentimental music playing]
Thank you
for bringing us all together
under one roof.
[Rafael] Thank you, heaven.
[Sawyer] So to, um...
to family.
[Rafael speaking Spanish]
[speaking Spanish]
[Mael in English]
Thanks, Sawyer.
-Appreciate you.
-Yeah.
[sentimental music continues]
I didn't think you had it
in you doing what you did.
I'm not proud of it.
The world's a cruel place.
You did what you had to do.
It doesn't feel very good.
No shit.
But you're a Clarkman.
[inhales deeply]
It's not about
what's right, what's easy.
It's about what's necessary.
I was just waiting
for the inevitable insult.
Auntie Hunter.
-Well, that's fucking terrible.
-[chuckles]
More like Cunty Hunter,
I think.
I buy that.
Not a bad ring to it.
[chuckles]
[alarm ringing]
[Hunter] Those motherfuckers.
[foreboding music playing]
[door opens]
[gun cocks]
[phone buzzing]
[Rafael] Ah...
Yeah, boss?
Raf, those fucks are back!
I'm already on my way.
[Rafael] Oh, shit!
Hey, hey, wait!
Wait right there!
Don't go on to
the property, yeah?
We're right behind you!
Mael!
[foreboding music continues]
[shouts]
Mael, I need you right now!
Come down!
[speaking Spanish]
[Rafael in English]
I'm sorry, but I need you.
-Where are you going?
-[Rafael] It's Hunter.
[speaking Spanish]
[Mael in English] What?
[Rafael speaking Spanish]
[suspenseful music playing]
[in English] Fuck.
Where are they?
[cocks gun]
[suspenseful music continues]
Fuckers.
I advise you
to drop the gun, Ms. Clarkman.
Yeah, four of you assholes,
and I'm gonna drop this?
What's a girl like you
doing all the way out here
so late at night
alone?
Well, you and your boys
have been lacing my water.
I didn't think it'd take you
this long to figure it out.
Guess you Clarkmans
aren't as sharp
as you think you are.
You don't understand
who you're dealing with.
Right back at you.
You think because you inherited
all this land and wealth
that you actually deserve it?
You haven't earned anything.
Truth is, you fill
your farm with people like me
and have us do all the work.
It's called natural selection.
And my men
are nothing like you.
You're nothing but a thief
in a fucking suit.
You're the one
trespassing here, Ms. Clarkman.
In case you haven't noticed...
you are on my land
holding a gun on me and my men.
[intense music playing]
[gunshot]
[men grunting]
[grunts]
[panting]
Anyone ever tell you
you hit like a bitch?
-[henchman] Oh, yeah?
-[Hunter] Yeah.
[Hunter groans]
[Hunter chokes]
[Hunter wheezing]
[intense music continues]
Fucking drugstore
cowboy motherfucker.
-[gunshot]
-[groans]
[Hunter gasping]
Natural selection.
[solemn music playing]
[Mael] Has, where
are you going--
Hassie, wait!
-Has, would you--
-[Hassie gasps]
Hunter!
[gasps] Hunter?
[Hassie panting]
-What happened?
-[Hunter gasping]
-What do I do?
-[Rafael] Put pressure
on the wound!
Direct pressure.
We should
get her into the truck.
[Mael] There's no fucking
service out here!
[Hassie] Talk to me.
Talk to me.
It was Roy.
[Hassie breathes heavily]
Don't fuck it up.
-Hey, hey.
-[wheezing]
No, Hunter.
Stay with me, stay with me.
Stay awake, come on. Come on.
Hunter! No!
Call my dad!
You gotta call my dad!
Come on, Hunter!
Hey, hey!
[Hassie breathes shakily]
Hunter!
Hunter.
[somber music playing]
[somber music continues]
[Ximena in Spanish]
[in English] Taking a look
at the phase one timeline,
and I got to tell you,
I think we can do better,
all right?
[Susanna] Roy!
-Susanna?
-[Rowan] I tried to stop her,
Dad. I'm sorry.
How dare you! Fucking asshole!
-[Roy] Calm down!
-[Susanna grunts]
Let go of me!
[Susanna] You are not
a businessman.
You are a fucking thug!
[Susanna breathing heavily]
Our alarms got triggered.
Someone was trespassing
on our property.
She had a gun. It was dark.
Susanna, it was an accident.
[Susanna] You're a liar.
[Roy] Okay.
You know
that I have tried
everything I can
to persuade your husband
to hand over
the land peacefully.
But like most white
country club assholes,
he is stupid
and he is stubborn.
Our offer was generous
and legitimate.
Look how he responded.
Look at what he
and Hunter did
to my property,
to my own son!
Are you gonna play the victim?
You pushed him to it.
[scoffs]
Susanna...
I told you.
I told you that land
was gonna be mine
one way or the other.
What the fuck
did you think
was gonna happen?
[door opens]
My son.
Leon!
[Leon] All this time...
I thought you had
actually changed.
That we could build
something together.
[Roy] We still can.
Look around you, son.
Hmm?
Do you think that,
that they would...
they would just give
someone like you
or me, all of this?
You've never
tasted desperation.
I have.
This world...
this is the world
that they built,
and this is how it works.
Stop trying to hide
your monstrosity...
with that twisted sense
of social justice.
You're a murderer.
All right.
All right, listen.
Leon,
when you take my place
at the head of the table,
none of this will matter.
We will be legitimate
and everything
will be forgiven.
Son...
Son... we are
the American dream.
[in Spanish]
[Rowan] Leon, I swear
on my life.
I had nothing
to do with this, okay?
I would never...
I'm sorry. I know
that you two--
You wouldn't
kill anyone, Ro.
I know that.
So why are you leaving, then?
Isn't that what you wanted?
You get to have him
all to yourself.
To him, I'm still the mistake
that ruined his marriage, okay?
I am just a reminder
of a woman
that he can't stand.
If I don't step in
and help him achieve
this wet dream of his,
then I'm out.
What am I supposed to do?
What do you think I'm doing?
[car door opens]
You don't have to be like him.
I hope you realize it
before it's too late.
[softly] Fuck. Fuck.
[glass shatters]
[coughs]
[slurps]
[exhales]
[coughs]
[retching]
[coughing]
[spits]
[breathing heavily]
[exhales]
[rifle cocking]
[gunshot]
What are you doing out here?
I could ask you the same thing,
[rifle cocking]
Go back to the house.
I know that rifle.
[sighs in exasperation]
He showed it to me.
The unregistered one.
[Sawyer] Yeah.
It's for culling sick dogs.
[gunshot]
[whispers] Right.
This particular dog
has private security.
Except this lobo
likes to take walks
in his field...
every day.
Get in touch with his feelings.
[gunshot]
Did I ever tell you
about your
great grandfather?
No, I don't think so.
Yeah? [groans]
He, uh...
came to California
over 100 years ago.
And he bought
this little ranch
with the money
that he made
drilling wells in,
down in Kern County.
He didn't have much.
[sighs] But...
he had this land.
And one day,
this government man
comes around
and wants to build
a railroad right
through his property.
Tries to extort him.
Intimidates him.
Threatens his family.
So a few days later,
your great grandfather
sends him word,
he's willing to sell.
And then
that government man
is found at the end
of his railroad tracks
with a bullet
between his eyes.
Nobody came by the ranch again.
That's why the...
railroad curves
around this property.
[rifle cocking]
That's what you do.
To people who behave
like animals.
[gunshot]
[exhales]
It doesn't matter
what happens to me,
I'm already gone.
Matters to me.
He shot down my girl, Hassie.
And I... [hesitates]
...I wasn't there.
[breath trembling]
I wasn't there to protect her.
Dad, it wasn't your fault.
[grunts softly]
Nobody crosses
a Clarkman
and gets away with it.
Nobody.
-[rifle cocks]
-[exhales]
-Hassie?
-[rifle cocks]
Do you see that little boy?
-[Sawyer groans]
-Dad!
Dad!
[Hassie] Help!
Help!
[Susanna] Thank you
for coming, Doctor.
We'll see you soon.
[door opens]
What happened?
What did he say?
[Susanna] He drained
what fluid he could,
adjusted his meds,
but taking him
to the hospital now
won't make any difference.
We just need to keep him
as comfortable as we can.
[Hassie] Hey.
Are you awake?
How long?
[Susanna] Mm...
He said days,
but I think that's hopeful.
[door opens]
[door closes]
[intense music playing]
[birds chirping]
[wind blowing]
[slurps]
[dramatic music playing]
[birds screeching]
[Mael] Hassie, stop it!
Hass? Stop!
Stop! What were you thinking?
-Stop! Stop!
-[Hassie crying]
Stop! It's me. It's me.
It's me.
It's okay. You gotta stop now.
-You gotta stop, it's me.
-[Hassie sobbing]
He killed my sister.
[Mael] It's me. You gotta stop.
[sobbing loudly]
[sobbing continues]
[Mael] I've never seen you
like that before, Hassie.
What were you thinking?
My sister's dead.
What was I supposed to do?
I don't know.
All right? I don't know.
But that wasn't you.
Maybe it was.
What are you saying?
Help me understand.
What does that mean?
What if this is just who I am?
What if it is?
What if it's just in my blood
and... and I don't like it,
but I can't get
away from it?
And, and, and it's...
it's just always
gonna be there?
You said that it was
this place.
Your parents, your mom
and dad, all right?
You said that, not me.
-I said I was--
-You said that.
I said I was scared
of being like them.
Maybe it's because I am.
And I'm just tired
of pretending
that I'm not.
No, you don't mean that.
I just want you to know
who you're with.
[sighs heavily]
You don't think I know?
I know exactly who you are,
and I love you.
You know that.
I love our baby. You know that.
I am here if you are here.
I am, yeah.
Okay.
-Okay.
[Sawyer] Mael told me
what happened.
Honey?
You'd have ruined
your life for that
piece of shit.
He's not worth it.
I'm glad you didn't.
[Hassie] What's going on?
[Ximena] Hassie.
[Hassie] Where are you going?
[Sawyer] I mean, I would
have been happy to.
I've done terrible things.
All in the name of...
protecting this land
and my family and apologizing.
[Susanna] Your father
is practically gone.
So I think it's about time
we just had a real talk.
He always knew
I was pushing
for this deal.
That's not a secret.
And if he had taken it,
we'd all still be here.
You're so fucking cold.
[Susanna] I am whatever
I needed to be.
I'll always be grateful.
My son wouldn't be here
if it wasn't for you.
[Susanna] You're not seeing
the big picture.
[Hassie sighs]
Taking this deal with Roy
is the only way
to protect the future
of this family.
-Taking the deal with Roy--
-[Susanna] Yes!
[Hassie] Roy!
The guy who killed
your daughter?
We have no family left
because of fucking Roy.
[Ximena] After everything
that has happened,
I just know in my heart
that this place will
never know peace, Hassie.
It's time for all of us
to move on.
Start all over again.
I'm done.
It's over.
It's all on you now.
You have to decide
what you're gonna do
with the land.
What's best for your family.
[sighs heavily]
Maybe I could have
done things different.
Maybe you can.
Hassie, this family is
you and me
and your baby.
Your baby.
[reflective music playing]
Hassie, sign the papers.
I can't imagine
my child not
growing up here.
It's home.
[Ximena in Spanish]
[in Spanish]
[Ximena speaking]
[both laugh]
-[door closes]
-[in English] Hey, babe.
How'd it go? Are you okay?
[inhales]
I couldn't do it.
Wait, wait. Why not?
What's happening?
Hey.
We talked about this.
We need to leave.
And go where?
I'll figure it out.
I'll find a place.
And then what?
Then what if
we have to run again?
I don't want that for you.
I don't want that
for our child.
You once said
that this place
was home.
Do you still believe that?
Yes. I do.
You guys have always
been here for me
more than my own family.
I don't know
where I would be
without you.
You're asking
for too much, Hassie.
I'm sorry, but no.
[Rafael] We've given
our entire lives
to your father.
To this place.
We can't keep
sacrificing ourselves
to protect something
that belongs to someone else.
-Not anymore.
-Yep. No more.
But what...
what if... what if
it didn't belong
to someone else?
I want you guys to have it.
Make it what we couldn't.
This place doesn't need me.
It needs you.
I mean, is he about done?
'Cause I actually have
do have things I need
to get done today.
I don't know.
What use are you? God.
[Roy] Apologies for the delay.
I had some business
to attend to.
I'm glad to see
that you agreed to stay
a little bit longer.
-Here, Roy, listen--
-Susanna...
it is best if you let me
do the talking.
[Ro] What the fuck
are they doing?
You stay out of this.
Dad?
-No. No!
-[Susanna] What...
the actual fuck is this?
[plastic rustling]
[Susanna] Roy?
[Roy] Please have a seat.
[Susanna] What are you
playing at?
[Roy] I said have a seat.
[Susanna] Oh, my God.
I just spoke with the governor.
I have done everything
I possibly can.
He's not giving us
any more time.
So this deal has to happen,
and it has to happen tonight.
[Ro] Fuck. Don't... Dad!
Do you recognize this gun?
It's yours.
It's from the glove box
of your car.
[breathing shakily] Roy, stop.
-Roy--
-Those dead ICE agents,
I need you to tell me
where they are.
Just stop!
-[gunshot]
-[screaming]
-Stop. What are you doing?
-Harry! Harry!
Just put it down! Put it down!
What are you doing?
Put it down!
-Dad, put it down!
-[Susanna screaming]
[Susanna wailing]
All right, you see, Susanna?
You just shot yourself
in the leg.
You're not gonna live
unless you get immediate
medical attention.
You have lost
your fucking mind!
Where are those bodies?
[screaming] I don't know!
-Where are the bodies?
-Dad!
-[screams] I don't know!
-Stop!
Sawyer never told anyone,
not even Hunter.
Who knows then?
Well, maybe we can...
[hesitating]
...have him stay
at my cousin's in Modesto
while Hassie deals with this,
and we're sure
that he'll be fine
to come back
[in Spanish]
[in English] So you're not
worried that they will go
looking for him there?
Huh?
[in Spanish]
[in English] I left her
with her dad. I think
they need some time, so...
I know that you don't
believe in this,
but it's something here
in my gut
that is telling me
we should still leave.
[Mael] Ma.
I think Hassie
is doing
the right thing.
Okay? And you know what?
I believe in her,
so, I don't know,
maybe it's time
you start taking
your own advice
and you start believing
in her, too.
-'Cause--
-[knocking at door]
[speaking Spanish]
[in English] Ugh, what, are we
expecting company?
-No, we're not.
-Ma.
[in Spanish]
[breathing heavily] Hi,
I'm so sorry
my tire just blew out on me,
and I don't have service
all the way out here, um...
Can I borrow your phone?
How did you get in here?
This is private property.
I'm sorry.
-[henchman yelling]
-[Rafael groaning]
-Pa! What the fuck?
-Rafael!
No!
Mael!
[Mael groaning]
[Ximena] No! Mael?
No!
Hello, Mael.
[breathing heavily] Pa...
[Roy] I am trying
to get your father
to help me with something.
And we thought
we would get your input.
Don't hurt him, please.
[in Spanish]
[in English] No.
They think they're cowboys.
They jump on their horses,
wear their leather boots.
They think they're
these mythical figures,
fighting for every last scrap.
Well,
maybe they're right, huh?
They are cowboys
in that they are ignorant
and backward.
[Rafael] No! Please!
[Roy] Tell me
where the bodies are.
No?
No.
No! Stop!
-[Rafael screams]
-[Roy] I'm sure you're
tired by now...
breaking your back for a man
who only sees you
as cheap labor.
I know.
My mother worked the fields.
She worked, and she worked
until the last day of her life.
Amazing, hmm? Isn't it?
What a parent will do
to give their children
a better life.
Don't throw
your son's life away.
No. No, no, no, no.
He doesn't know anything.
-Don't tell him anything, Pa.
-[Rafael] No! No! Don't do it!
You'll never get away with it!
Get away with it?
-Who cares about a couple
of undocumented Mexicans?
-[Mael] Don't tell him shit.
-Shut up!
-No! [speaks Spanish]
[Rafael in English]
No! No! Stop!
-Stop.
-[Roy] Last time! Last time!
Last time!
[screams]
[Roy] Where are they?
-Okay, okay!
-[Roy] Where?
I'll tell you!
Get Hassie Clarkman back here
by whatever means necessary.
Dad, this is getting messy.
Did you not hear me?
What are we doing?
You get this done,
or you can fuck off
with your brother.
[intense music playing]
[Frank] All right, let's go.
On your knees.
[Mael groans]
[Rafael] Here.
[Roy] You're certain?
[gasping]
[Ximena breathlessly] Hassie...
Hassie.
They took the boys.
-They took them.
-What do you mean?
-They took Mael and Raf.
-Who? Who?
The house was...
They just came
and they took them.
-What do you mean?
-[sobbing] I told you so.
They are looking
for those bodies!
[Sawyer] Hassie.
Hassie.
They took my...
-[Sawyer] Hassie.
-[Hassie mumbles]
What's going on?
[suspenseful music playing]
[Sawyer] I'll say I did it.
Then you'll be free and clear.
-What?
-[groans softly]
I know that you know
that I called those ICE agents.
But they came for Mael
because of me
and because
of your mother, because...
we didn't want you with him.
[floor creaking]
I'm a bad man, Ximena.
I know.
I should've called them off.
I shouldn't have called them
in the first place.
I'm ashamed of myself.
I'm deeply sorry
for any pain I ever caused you.
A lot of things
wouldn't have happened
if it wasn't for me.
You didn't pull the trigger.
True.
But I put you there.
You want your kids
to stand on your shoulders?
Don't be like me.
Please don't be
like your mother.
You get to be who you want.
I hope you realize that
before it's too late.
It's time.
You know what to do.
[sighs]
[door creaks]
[Roy in Spanish]
[in Spanish]
[in English] Hey,
we got something here.
[intense music playing]
You were saying?
[camera shutter clicking]
That's it.
This is what we need.
Clarkmans are done.
Let's go get this deal settled.
[Frank] Boss.
[suspenseful music playing]
Rowan, what are you doing?
Let them go!
They're done! We have them.
Look for yourself.
Dad, all of this shit
needs to stop.
Just let them go.
I knew this would happen
one day.
[gun cocks]
Are you gonna fucking shoot me?
Fuck you!
Dad...
Mael!
[Rafael speaking Spanish]
[Hassie] Stop it!
Get away from them!
Miss Clarkman.
We found something
that belongs to you.
Step away from him.
You think I won't?
-[gunshot]
-Don't fuck with me!
Get down! Get on your knees!
Drop it!
[Roy] Do
what the young lady says.
You killed my sister.
I did.
[gunshot]
[Hassie panting]
You killed my daughter,
you goddamn fucking Chihuahua.
That's on you!
I told you to take the deal.
Goodbye, Roy.
[grunts] Out of the way,
Hassie.
No.
He deserves to die.
He killed our girl.
He does.
[Sawyer] Get out
of the way, Hassie.
-No.
-Get out of the way.
-Please, let me kill him.
-No, Dad.
-[sobbing] Please,
let me kill him.
No, Dad.
It's okay.
[helicopter approaching]
[police sirens wailing]
[Roy] Fuck.
Everybody freeze!
Drop your weapons!
Now!
[Baxter] Let's go. Let's go.
What the hell is going on here?
Enos, get an ambulance
here right now.
Mr. Reyes,
what are you doing here?
-This isn't your property.
-Sawyer Clarkman
did this to me.
Baxter, that piece of shit
murdered my daughter.
[Baxter]
All right, that's enough.
Well, I think I know
who these two are.
Well, well...
Nice to see you, Miss Clarkman.
We've been looking for you
and your boyfriend here
for quite some time.
All right. We'll sort this out
at the station.
[groaning] Get off me!
-All right, all right.
-This isn't over.
[Baxter] Hey, get the boy, too.
-Wait. I was the one
who called you here.
-[Mael] Hassie, no. Just stop.
Stop.
-It was me.
-Sheriff, that's bullshit,
all right?
She's lying to you.
-Hassie, stop!
-I killed them. Both of them.
Mael had nothing to do with it.
-Just... Stop!
-It was me.
-Are you sure about that?
-Yeah.
[Sawyer] She was protecting
herself.
I told her to run away.
And then I buried
those ICE agents.
[Baxter] Sir, are you okay?
You don't look too good.
-Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
-[Hassie] Dad.
[Baxter] Hang on. Hang on.
-[Baxter] Harlan!
Where's that ambulance?
[Hassie softly] Dad...
Dad.
Hey... sweetheart...
[crying]
[solemn music playing]
I wanted you to see
your grandchild.
[Sawyer] That's who he is.
[Hassie sobbing]
[Sawyer] Hassie.
I can see him.
I see him.
[sighs]
He...
He has your eyes.
And you've got mine.
[gasping]
[crying] I love you, Dad.
I love you.
[Sawyer] My dearest loves,
I am so sorry
to have left you earlier
than I imagined.
I lived my whole life
believing the world
to be a cold place.
I was certain
that you had to be the same
in order to survive it,
to leave something
of value behind.
[Hassie] Mom, it's okay.
I'm okay.
They're offering me a deal.
They don't want this
to go to trial.
Everyone will know
that the two agents
were out of bounds,
so I'll be out in three years.
Can you forgive me?
I already have.
Mom, you wanted to get away
from the ranch
ever since I can remember.
Just...
go.
Live your life
for yourself for a while.
What about the ranch?
It's gonna be different
this time.
I don't have to be a Clarkman
in the Clarkman way.
[Sawyer] But I failed
to acknowledge
that legacy is more
than holding on to our past
and waiting for an old,
ill-conceived glory
to return somehow.
Maybe instead, it can be hope.
Hope that what
we lived together
can guide you towards the light
and not the darkness.
Hope that whatever changes
can always be for the better.
If I could have it my way,
I'd have that be my legacy.
Hey, buddy, come here.
-How are you doing?
-[boy] Good.
How are my boys?
-Hey, Mama.
-Hi.
[Sawyer] That the choices
you make
forge the right path
for your family.
Do whatever lessons
I've taught you,
the relationships you build
give you the strength to care
and the courage
to do better this time.
[ Prisoner of My Name playing]
♪ Take me down
To the foot of the grave ♪
♪ I'm a soul
That cannot be saved ♪
♪ The hill's only know
What we did for the gold ♪
♪ I'm a prisoner of my name ♪
♪ Hell ♪
-♪ Hell ♪
-♪ I'm a prisoner of my name ♪
♪ When you poured in
The blood ♪
♪ And you're drug
Through the mud ♪
♪ It's so damn hard
To complain ♪
♪ Yeah, I learned it
From my daddy ♪
♪ And although he made me sad ♪
♪ He did the best he could
To protect me ♪
♪ With a finger
On the trigger ♪
♪ It was ever getting bigger ♪
♪ It's a story
You won't live to tell ♪
♪ No, I don't got
A lot to give ♪
♪ But I'm going
To give them hell ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm going
♪ Hell ♪
-♪ Hell ♪
-♪ I'm a prisoner of my name ♪
♪ Hell ♪
-♪ Hell ♪
-♪ I'm a prisoner of my name ♪
[vocalizing]
♪ When I wake in the morning ♪
♪ I can hear my baby yawning ♪
♪ It's a beautiful
Brand-new day ♪
[song fades]